知道了吧 你吃的这个 不算是真的酸奶酪
so you see what you eating is not technically yogurt,
因为里面没有足够的 活的嗜酸培养菌
because it doesn't have enough live acidophilus cultures.
只不过是冰牛奶里加了点 角叉胶 增加粘稠度
It's really just ice milk with carrageenan added for thickness.
喔 真有意思哈
Oh,that's very interesting.
它也不真是粉红色 也没有天然浆果粒
It's also not pink and has no berries.
嗯 可这也没有回答我的问题呐
Yeah,but it doesn't really answer my question.
你问的啥问题?
What was your question again?
你要来点儿不?
Do you want some?
对对 不用了
Right. No.
- 我受不了乳糖的 - 对哦
- I'm lactose intolerant. - Right.
- 吃了会放屁的 - 好吧 明白了
- So,gas. - Yeah,got it.
那么... 晚安了
Well... good night.
你这是做什么呢?
What are you doing?
哦 那边有阵风
Oh,there's a draft.
我没觉得有风啊
I didn't feel a draft.
那我们还是去... 你的...
Why don't we just go into,uh,your...
我说 也许我们不该那么着急
Yeah,you know what,maybe we should slow things down a little.
不 我不是说要去你公寓 去急着干嘛干嘛
No,no,I didn't mean to go into your apartment to go fast.
当然了 我知道
No,I know.
我知道你不是那意思 只是... 这才是咱俩第一次约会
I know what you meant,it's just... this is only our first date.
嗯 好啊 没问题
Yeah,okay,sure,no problem.
那我们就先想想 下次要去哪儿 准备啥时候到那儿
Why don't we just figure out where we're going and when we want to get there,
这样距离除以时间 就知道速度了呗
and then rate of speed equals distance over time.
问题解决
Solve for R.
我们也可以到时候再想嘛
Or we could just wing it.
那没准也行
That might work,too.
- 晚安 莱纳德- 晚安
- Good night,Leonard. - Good night.
他来了 快上屏保!
He's coming-- screensaver!
嘿 莱纳德约会怎么样哇?
Oh,hey,Leonard. How was your date?
要你管
Bite me.
谢尔顿 你怎么能傻坐着 眼睁睁看他们监视我呢?
Sheldon,how could you just sit there and let them spy on me?
他们油菜啊 莱纳德
They were clever,Leonard.
他们完全明白 我对你那些破事儿 一点兴趣没有
They exploited my complete lack of interest in what you were doing.
你还该谢谢我们呢
You should thank us.
要是后来人想弄明白 你和佩妮的恋情为啥会土崩瓦解
When future generations try to determine why your relationship with Penny crashed and burned,
这玩意儿就是黑匣子呐!
this right here is the black box.
你胡说什么 约会挺好的
What are you talking about? The date went fine.
拜托 她都说了 想要慢慢来
Dude,she said she wants to slow things down.
好吧 她是说了 想要慢慢来
Okay,so she said she wants to slow things down.
意思差不多就是 "今天的晚餐我非常喜欢
It's like saying,"I'm really enjoying this meal.
我得慢慢来 好好回味一下"
I'm going to slow down and savor it."
才怪 她的意思是 "这鱼真难吃死了
No,it's like,"This fish tastes bad,
我得慢慢来 吐光了它"
so I'm gonna slow down and spit it out."
- 这臭鱼说的就是你! - 我才不是这臭鱼呢
- You being the fish. - I'm not the fish.
真的? 你俩定了下一次约会吗?
Oh,really? Did you make a second date?
这倒没有... 我们说好了 到时候再想
Well,no,we sort of decided to wing it.
得了吧 连我都觉得这太逊了
Oh,even I know that's lame.
行啊 咱就说说你的假设
Okay,all right,let's assume your hypothesis.
我们一起去吃饭 有说有笑 有吻有抱
We went to dinner,we talked,we laughed,we kissed.
这还能错到哪儿去啊?
Where could I have possibly gone wrong?
你好好想想 莱纳德
Think back,Leonard.
再小的事情都能让女人爆发
The littlest things can set women off.
比方说 "嘿 这服务生真辣 我打赌 肯定能让她跟咱回家"
Like,"Hey,the waitress is hot,I bet we could get her to come home with us."
或者 "你妈妈有多重呐?
Or,"How much does your mom weigh?
我想知道我搭上的是啥样的妞儿"
I want to know what I'm getting into."
这种话我才不会说
I didn't say anything like that.
很好 因为这么说不管用
Good,'cause they don't work.
她们也不关心 你是不是盯着她们 呼吸加速
They also don't care for it if you stare at them and hyperventilate.
挺惨的 在我们家 这就像是家族传统
Sadly,that's my home run swing.
我说 一切都挺好的
Look,everything went fine.
连事先准备的一些开场白都没用到呢
I didn't even have to refer to my impromptu conversation starters.
走廊对面那个女孩 就是喜欢我嘛
That woman across the hall is into me.
咱还是看带子吧
Let's go to the tape.
你瞧她临别一吻的时候 那反应
Look at her reaction to the good night kiss.
呼吸平稳 瞳孔没有放大 胸口也没啥起伏
No change in respiration,pupils un-dilated,no flushing of the chest.
这特写镜头拍的真赞
Nice close-up,by the way.
有意思嘿 她的下巴很紧 也没有用舌头
Interesting. Her jaws are clenched: no tongue access.
对于寻偶期的人类来说 这可不是啥好消息
Clearly a bad sign amongst mating humans.
这怎么就不是好消息了
That's not a bad sign.
得了吧 还不如说你们是两只鬣蜥 只是喉部没有垂肉罢了
Please,you might as well have been two iguana with no dewlap enlargement.
最糟的就是 这会儿你不在她家 而在这里!
And the worst sign of all is you're here and not there.
我不在她家 因为我也决定慢慢来 这个...
I'm not there because I'm taking things slow,which,
跟你们比起来 都快接近星际速度了
by the way,compared to you guys,approaches warp speed.
快把摄像头给我撤了
And take down that camera.
他心里没牵没挂的时候 真有意思多了
He was a lot more fun when he had no hope.
给他点时间吧
Give him time.
《生活大爆炸》
第二季  第01集
你好啊 佩妮
Oh,hi,Penny.
顺便说句 2号机器的热水不足 别深色浅色混着洗
FYI,the hot water is inadequate on machine two,so colors only,
4号机器呢 洗衣程序中 还是会提前放出织物柔顺剂
and four is still releasing the fabric softener too early in the cycle,
所以你那些精致的衣服 还是别用那台了
so I'd avoid using that for your delicates.
谢了
Thanks.
老天爷啊...
Oh,good Lord...
你还不如把衣服拿到河边 搁在石头上猛捶一阵
why don't you just take your clothes down to the river and beat them with a rock?
谢尔顿 我问你个问题行不?
Sheldon,can I ask you a question?
我当然最好你别问 不过也不会阻止你
I would prefer that you not,but I won't go so far as to forbid it.
那... 我就当你同意了...
All right,I heard yes,so...
我想问问你
Okay,here's my question.
莱纳德以前有没有 跟正常的女孩子约会过?
Has Leonard ever dated,you know,a regular girl?
我想你指的 应该不是消化功能正常吧
Well,I assume you're not referring to digestive regularity.
要是那样的话 我想这问题问的不合适
Because I've come to learn that such inquiries are inappropriate.
我是说 他有没有跟 没那么大学问的女孩子谈过?
No,I meant,has he ever been involved with someone who wasn't a brainiac?
话说几年前 他确实跟一个 学法国文学的女博士有过一段儿
Well,a few years ago,he did go out with a woman who had a PhD in French literature.
这还不算有大学问?
How is that not a brainiac?
理由一 她是法国人
Well,for one thing,she was French.
理由二 她读的是文学
For another,it was literature.
那你觉得...
So...
如果我和莱纳德继续好下去 他会不会有一天觉得我很没劲啊?
do you think that if Leonard and I keep dating,he'll eventually get bored with me?
- 那得看情况 - 什么情况?
- That depends. - On what?
- 你懂量子物理吗? - 不懂
- Do you have a working knowledge of quantum physics? - No.
- 你会说克林贡语(《星际迷航》影片中的外星语)吗? - 不会
- Do you speak Klingon? - No.
- 你会耍牌吗? - 行了 我说...
- You know any card tricks? - Okay,you know what...
我明白了
I get it.
莱纳德和一个服务员兼二流演员 没有共同语言
Leonard has no business being involved with a waitress-slash-actress
而且她还骗他说 上完了社区大学 心里正发慌呢
who felt so insecure that she lied to him about finishing community college.
你为什么撒谎?
Why would you lie about that?
他总是在说这大学怎样 那个研究生院怎么样 我就...
Well,he was going on and on about this college and that grad school,and I...
我不想让他觉得我很傻很衰嘛
I didn't want him to think I was some kind of stupid loser.
你觉得"很傻很衰"的反义词 是"社区大学毕业生"?
You thought the opposite of "stupid loser" was "community college graduate"?
很多成功人士 都是从社区大学毕业的
You know,there are a lot of successful people in this country who are community college graduates.
没错 可你哪个都挨不上边
Yeah,but you are neither.
对 好吧 你得替我保密
Right. Okay,look,this is between you and me.
啥也不要告诉莱纳德
You cannot tell Leonard any of this.
- 你要我保守秘密? - 是的
- You're asking me to keep a secret? - Yeah.
那真对不起了 你应该在说出秘密前 表达出要我保密的意思
Well,I'm sorry,but you would have had to express that desire before revealing the secret,
我好选择 到底要不要替你保密
so that I could choose whether or not I wanted to accept the covenant of secret keeping.
你事后再说 这怎么行呢
You can't impose a secret on an ex post facto basis.
什么?
What?
保守秘密是一项艰巨复杂的任务
Secret keeping is a complicated endeavor.
不但要注意说的话
One has to be concerned not only about what one says,
还得注意面部表情 习惯性反应
but about facial expressions,autonomic reflexes.
我说谎的时候 因为紧张产生的壁虱(tick) 比莱姆关节炎研究设备产生的还多
When I try to deceive,I myself have more nervous tics than a Lyme disease research facility.
这是笑话啊
It's a joke.
同音词嘛 "tick"是指
It relies on the homonymic relationship between "tick,"
吸血寄生虫（壁虱） 而"tic"是无意识的肌肉痉挛
the bloodsucking arachnid,and "tic," the involuntary muscular contraction.
我自己编的
I made it up myself.
听着 如果莱纳德发现我说谎 我一定羞愧自尽了
Okay,look,if Leonard finds out that I lied,I will absolutely die of embarrassment.
生理学上讲是不可能的
Physiologically impossible.
哦 谢尔顿 拜托
Oh,Sheldon,please.
我是以朋友的名义请求你
Look,I am asking you as a friend.
照你这么说 朋友就要无条件的保守秘密?
So you're saying that friendship contains within it an inherent obligation to maintain confidences?
是啊
Well,yeah.
有意思
Interesting.
再一个问题 或许应该这样问
One more question,and perhaps I should have led with this.
我们什么时候成朋友了?
When did we become friends?
也就是说 要不被总部守护先知选中 我就成不了绿灯侠(漫画人物)
i.e.,I couldn't become Green Lantern unless I was chosen by the Guardians of Oa,
但如果给我足够的启动资金和 足够的科研设备 我就能成为蝙蝠侠
but given enough start-up capital and an adequate research facility,I could be Batman.
- 你能成为蝙蝠侠? - 当然 我就是蝙蝠侠 看见没?
- You could be Batman? - Sure. I'm Batman. See?
- 嗨 伙计们 - 嗨 佩妮
- Hi,guys. - Hi,Penny.
佩妮 你周五晚上有空的话 我们去看电影吧
Penny,if you're not doing anything Friday night,I thought maybe we could go see a movie.
呃 我周五晚上要轮班
Oh,um,you know,I think I have the dinner shift on Friday.
好吧 周六呢?
Okay,what about Saturday?
说不准 经理还没公布排班表呢
You know,I'm not sure; the manager hasn't posted the schedule yet.
- 出来了 我再告诉你? - 很好
- How about I let you know? - Great.
那你知道了就告诉我 好的 那...
So you just let me know when you know. Okay,so...
天呐 我就是那条臭鱼
Oh,God,I am the bad fish.
我哪做错了?
What did I do wrong?
你为什么问我?
Why are you asking me?
你和佩妮的事儿 除了你已经告诉我的 我啥也不知道
I have no information about your interactions with Penny other than what you have provided me,
我也没有本事学到
nor do I have any method of learning such things.
- 这话什么意思? - 没什么
- What does that mean? - Nothing.
你说的倒像是 我和佩妮背地里通了气
You seem to be implying an informational back-channel
很明显 这是没有的事
between me and Penny where obviously none exists.
没 我没觉得
No,I didn't.
我想你要注意你的表达了 先生
I just think you need to be careful how you phrase things,sir.
你怎么回事?
What's going on with you?
这问题我也得问问你吧
I might ask you the same question.
那些跟我无关的事儿 你何必非要把我扯进去?
Why do you insist on attempting to drag me into matters which have nothing to do with me,
都是你和佩妮之间的事 我跟她连话都不怎么说的
but exist between you and Penny,a person to whom I barely speak?
你脸怎么了?
What's wrong with your face?
我脸这样 没啥原因
There's no reason to bring my looks into this.
- 祝你今天过的愉快 莱纳德- 什么?
- Good day,Leonard. - What
我说 "祝你今天过的愉快"
I said,"Good day."
过的愉快?
Good day?
今天还为您供应 新鲜的阿拉斯加大马哈鱼
Also today,we have a fresh-caught Alaska salmon,
配上烧汁和糯米饭
and that's served with a teriyaki glaze and sticky rice.
今天的汤是...
Our soup of the day is...
你必须将我从我的誓言中解放出来
You must release me from my oath.
谢尔顿 我在工作
Sheldon,I'm working.
你们花几分钟决定一下吧
Why don't you take a minute to decide?
我不能保守你的秘密了 佩妮
I can't keep your secret,Penny.
我就像构象空间里 基于能量的内源蛋白 要折叠起来了 (fold 也有失败的意思)
I'm going to fold like an energy-based de novo protein in conformational space.
就像是文艺复兴时期的三联画 (教堂祭坛上的饰物 两翼可向内折叠)
Like a Renaissance tryptich.
还有廉价的西装
Like a cheap suit.
你保守个小秘密 咋就这么难呢?
Look,why is it so hard for you to keep one little secret?
我天生就保守不住!
I'm constitutionally incapable.
所以我上次申请那项高端政府研究奖学金 证明开不出来
That's why I was refused clearance for a very prestigious government research fellowship
项目里的超级对撞机 位于密歇根州 特拉弗斯城东南12.5英里的
at a secret military supercollider located beneath a fake agricultural station
一个空设的农学院地下
12.5 miles southeast of Traverse City,Michigan.
我没告诉过你啊
Which you did not hear about from me.
你就别老记着我说过...
Look,just forget I told you about me...
社区大学没毕业 好吗?
not graduating from community college,okay?
别老记着? 这能忘得掉吗?
Forget? You want me to forget?
我这脑子 啥东西忘得掉啊!
This mind does not forget.
从我妈给我断奶后 我就没忘掉过一件事
I haven't forgotten a single thing since the day my mother stopped breastfeeding me.
- 那天是周二 下着毛毛雨 - 好了...
- It was a drizzly Tuesday. - Okay...
你答应过我要保守秘密
Look,you promised me you would keep my secret,
那你就想个办法别漏嘴
so you're just gonna have to figure out a way to do it.
莱纳德我要搬出去
Leonard,I'm moving out.
什么叫"要搬出去"? 为什么?
What do you mean you're moving out? Why?
不一定非要有理由嘛
There doesn't have to be a reason.
是啊 总该有吧
Yeah,there kinda does.
不一定非得有
Not necessarily.
这是Munchausen三难推理的典型例子
This is a classic example of Munchausen's Trilemma.
要么就是 这个前提通过一系列 不断弱化的次前提 已经得到阐述
Either the reason is predicated on a series of sub-reasons leading to an infinite regression,
要么就是 能从所谓偶然的公理陈述中 找到答案
or it tracks back to arbitrary axiomatic statements,
也有可能是终极循环
or it's ultimately circular,
也就是说 因为我要搬出去 所以我要搬出去
i.e.I'm moving out because I'm moving out.
我还是不懂
I'm still confused.
莱纳德我已经说得够明白的了
Leonard,I don't see how I could have made it any simpler.
嘿 伙计们 还好吗?(蹩脚法语)
Hey,qu'est que s'up?
我们刚去看了塑化人体标本展
We just got back from that exhibit of those plasticized human cadavers.
那些个没皮的小妞儿 真是辣哟!
And some of those skinless chicks were Hot!
抱歉 我得去收拾了
If you'll excuse me,I'm going to pack.
他对我单纯的恋尸癖 反应还真大
That's kind of an overreaction to a little harmless necrophilia.
霍华德 不关你事 他说他要搬出去
It's not you,Howard. He says he's moving out.
你对他干了啥?
What did you do?
你改了电视机的对比度和亮度?
Did you change the contrast or brightness settings on the television?
没啊
No.
你在他面前扒了创可贴?
Did you take a Band-Aid off in front of him?
没
No.
你买了三无番茄酱? 忘了洗水池?
Did you buy generic ketchup,forget to rinse the sink,
还是隔着厕所门同他讲话?
talk to him through the bathroom door?
调了恒温器? 煮菜放了芫荽叶? "t"那音总是忘了发?
Adjust the thermostat,cook with cilantro,pronounce the "t" in often?
没有
No.
你是不是拿火车开玩笑了?
Did you make fun of trains?
没有 我啥都没干 他疯了
No,I didn't do anything. He's just gone insane.
也是 这天迟早会来的
Well,we all knew this day was coming.
你动作还真快
Well,that was fast.
这是我早准备好的避难行囊
It's my pre-packed disaster evacuation bag.
国土安全部推荐的
It's recommended by the Department of Homeland Security.
还有莎拉·康纳 ("终结者"女主人公)
And Sarah Connor.
你打算住哪儿?
Where are you going to live?
在我找到寓所之前 我先在朋友家挤挤
Until I find a permanent place,I will stay with friends.
回见
Bye.
呃... 你不能住我那儿
Well... you can't stay with me.
我的公寓小得可怜
I have a teeny-tiny apartment.
广纳宾客不正是"向人致敬"的一部分吗?
Excuse me,but isn't hosting guests an aspect of "manushya yajna,"
"向人致敬"不是印度五大宗教戒规之一吗?
one of the five central religious duties or sacrifices of the Hindu householder?
我讨厌火车
I hate trains.
别开玩笑了 你可喜欢火车了
Don't be ridiculous,you love trains.
啊 没错 来吧
Yes,I do. Come on.
回见 莱纳德
See you later,Leonard.
还真管用
This could work.
这栋楼有年头了
This is a very old building.
造了六十年了 以前是手表厂
60 years. It used to be a watch factory.
怎么了?
What?
你不担心残留在发光表盘里的镭吗?
Don't you worry about the residual radium from the luminous dials?
你干嘛要提!
Not until now!
我竟然没带盖格计数器 (用于测量放射性物质)
I can't believe I didn't bring my Geiger counter.
就在床头 我居然没拿
I had it on my bed and I didn't pack it.
那么... 谢尔顿 要是你觉得住着不舒服
Well,if you're not comfortable staying here,Sheldon...
我开玩笑的 我带来了
I'm kidding,I packed it.
是个笑话
It was a joke.
我就是要破坏你的语境期待
I was subverting the conversational expectations.
那叫啥来着 "出其不意"
I believe they call that the,uh,ol' switcharoo.
好极了
Terrific.
那女的是艾维雅·瑞儿（印度当红影星）吗?
Is that woman Aishwarya Rai?
是的 她是个很棒的演员吧
Yes,isn't she an amazing actress?
我倒觉得她是可怜虫心中的玛杜瑞·迪克西特 (印度90年代知名影星 后结婚生子)
Actually,I'd say she's a poor man's Madhuri Dixit.
你敢再说一遍!
How dare you!
艾维雅·瑞儿是我的女神
Aishwarya Rai is a goddess.
相比之下 玛杜瑞·迪克西特 就是得麻风病的妓女
By comparison,Madhuri Dixit is a leprous prostitute.
对不起 我没想到会冒犯你
Sorry,I didn't mean to offend you.
显然你不了解印度电影
Obviously,you're not that familiar with Indian cinema.
谁啊?
Who is it?
脱衣舞娘来喽!
Stripper-Gram!
交给你了
Tag,you're It.
你就不能把他塞进牛皮纸袋里 烧了算了?
Shouldn't you put him in a brown paper bag and set him on fire?
我从来没睡过气垫床
I've never slept on an air mattress before.
腰部都没东西撑着
No lumbar support whatsoever.
你大概是想睡公园的长椅上是吧
Maybe you'd be happier on a park bench.
我认为 你没有办法把长椅弄到这儿来
I don't see any way to get a park bench in here.
要换一下吗?
Do you want to switch?
不用了 这样挺好
No,that's fine.
睡在充气城堡上可舒服呢
I'm perfectly comfortable sleeping on a bouncy castle.
下床来 我和你换
Get out of bed. We're switching.
- 我没逼着你换 - 快下床!
- Now,only if you want to. - Just get in the bed!
这是怎么了?
What's going on?
你们两个臭小子 闹什么闹?
Are you boys roughhousing?
老妈 我们只是在聊天!
We're just talking,Ma!
要是你们再不给我安生点
If you don't settle down right now,
看我以后还让不让你去朋友家过夜!
I'm not going to let you have any more sleepovers!
老天啊 老妈 我都27了!
For God's sake,Ma,I'm 27 years old!
明天又不上学!
And it's not even a school night!
舒服了吧?
Comfy now?
那张哈莉·贝瑞(好莱坞女星 曾出演猫女)的海报让我有点紧张
That poster of Halle Berry is a little unnerving.
别看就是了
So don't look at it.
她是我第四爱的猫女郎
She's like my fourth favorite Catwoman.
不是吧
No kidding.
对 前三个是朱莉·纽曼 米切尔·菲佛尔 和伊尔特·基特
Yeah,Julie Newmar,Michelle Pfieffer,Eartha Kitt,and then her.
李·梅里韦瑟呢?
What about Lee Merriweather?
噢 我把她忘了
Oh,I forgot about Lee Merriweather.
好吧 终于搞定了
Well,I'm glad that's settled.
那哈莉·贝瑞只能排第五了
That makes Halle Berry my fifth favorite Catwoman.
朱莉·纽曼  米切尔·菲佛尔 伊尔特·基特  李·梅里韦瑟...
It's Julie Newmar,Michelle Pfieffer,Eartha Kitt,Lee Merriweather--
求求你了 睡觉吧
Please,I'm begging you. Go to sleep.
我在努力嘛 都在数猫女郎了
I'm trying. I'm counting Catwomen.
她在X战警里演的变种人倒是不赖
She did make a fine mutant in the X-Men movies,though.
噢 我求求你了
Oh,for God's sake.
X战警里我最喜欢的不是她
She's not my favorite of the X-Men.
要排序的话应该是:金钢狼 雷射眼
In order that would be: Wolverine,Cyclops--
噢 等等 我忘了X教授
Oh,wait,I forgot Professor X.
X教授 金钢狼 雷射眼 冰人 然后是暴风女 天使 还有野兽
Professor X,Wolverine,Cyclops,Iceman,then Storm,Angel,the Beast--
不对 等等 还有蓝魔人
No,wait,Nightcrawler.
X教授 蓝魔人 金钢狼 雷射眼 冰人 暴风女 天使...
Professor X,Nightcrawler,Wolverine,Cyclops,Iceman,then Storm,Angel...
来了!
I'm coming!
是他 我的老-伙-计
There he is. There my old buddy bud bud.
他是怎么了?
What's with him?
Koothrappali把他扔给了我 他睡不着觉
Koothrappali dumped him on me,and he couldn't get to sleep,
所以我给他倒了杯温牛奶 里面放了一把我妈的安眠药
so I gave him a glass of warm milk with a handful of my mom's Valium in it...
可他还是不肯住嘴 得了 还给你吧
but he still wouldn't shut up,so tag,you're It.
我回...来了
I'm ba-a-a-ack.
我还是不知道你为啥要走
I still don't know why you left.
不能告诉你
I can't tell you.
为什么?
Why not?
我答应过佩妮
I promised Penny.
你答应她什么了?
You promised Penny what?
我答应她保密啊
I wouldn't tell you the secret.
什么秘密? 快告诉我
What secret? Tell me the secret.
老妈在车里抽烟
Mom smokes in the car.
耶稣觉得没问题 不过不能告诉老爸
Jesus is okay with it but we can't tell Dad.
不是这个 另一个秘密
Not that secret. The other secret.
- 我是蝙蝠侠 嘘! - 我靠! 谢尔顿!
- I'm Batman-- Shh! - Damn it! Sheldon!
你说 佩妮跟你说了个秘密 什么秘密?
You said Penny told you a secret. What's the secret?
好吧 我告诉你 不过你不能告诉莱纳德
Okay,I'll tell you,but you can't tell Leonard.
我保证
I promise.
佩妮说她是社区大学毕业 其实没这回事
Penny lied about graduating from community college
因为她怕自己不够聪明 配不上莱纳德
'cause she's afraid she's not smart enough for Leonard.
不是我做错什么了? 是她的问题?
So it's nothing I did? It's her problem?
我喝了杯牛奶 味道真好玩儿
I drank milk that tasted funny.
佩妮觉得我太聪明 这也太搞笑了
Penny thinks I'm too smart for her. That's ridiculous.
我明白
I know.
你的大部分工作 都不是原创的
Most of your work is extremely derivative.
别担心 这就不是秘密了
And don't worry,that's not a secret.
谁都知道
Everybody knows.
听着 我已经知道我们之间的问题了 我也有了解决方案
Listen,I know what's been bothering you about us,and I have the answer.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
好的 首先 这不是谢尔顿的错
Okay,first,I want to say that it's not Sheldon's fault.
他已经很努力地替你保密了
He tried very hard to keep your secret.
要不是霍华德给他灌了安眠药 他是不会自掘坟墓的
If Howard hadn't drugged him,he would've taken it to his grave.
他告诉你了?
He told you?
是的 不过这没关系
Yes,but it's okay.
既然我们都知道问题何在 要解决岂不是很容易
Now that we know what the problem is there's a simple solution.
帕萨迪纳城市学院?(托福分数线最低的学校之一)
Pasadena City College?
"给你知识 给你乐趣"
A place for fun,a place for knowledge.
看见没? 这男的在玩沙包球 那女的会成为律师助手
See,this man here is playing hackey-sack,and this girl's gonna be a paralegal.
噢 我明白了
Oh,I get it.
莱纳德·霍夫施塔特博士没法和一个 没有名牌大学文凭的女孩子谈恋爱
Because Dr. Leonard Hofstadter can't date a girl without a fancy college degree.
嗯... 其实这也不是个名校
Well,it's really not that fancy.
只是城市学院而已
It's just a city college.
没错 不过要和你约会 总得有个学位什么的是吧?
Right,but I have to have some sort of degree to date you?
这对我而言一点都不重要
That doesn't matter to me at all.
所以如果我不聪明也没关系
So it's fine with you if I'm not smart.
绝对没关系
Absolutely.
好吧 这次我知道我错在哪儿了
Okay,this time,I know where I went wrong.
你能拿我怎么样啊?!
Bite me!